小镇疑云
第二季  第三集
翻译  草草
翻译  阿包包
翻译  unundu
翻译  持久
翻译  菲力
翻译  Michael
时间轴  讷讷
时间轴  阿包包
校对  青椒
校对 笨熊猫
后期  Sung
总监  面条打包子
《小镇疑云》前情提要
Previously on Broadchurch...
你认出扛着尸体的男人了吗
Did you recognise the man carrying the body?
是的
Yeah, I did.
你能在法庭上说出那个人的名字吗
Can you name that man for the court?
奈杰·卡特  他是我儿子
Nigel Carter. He's my son.
一定要办一个以丹尼命名的慈善会
There's going to be a charity in Danny's name.
有一个小组  跟已知的性犯罪者打交道
There's a small group. They work with known sex offenders.
一个女孩的尸体仍未找到  凶手逍遥法外
A girl's body is still missing. The killer is walking free.
那案子臭名远扬
That case is tainted.
没人愿意再碰它
Nobody wants to get near it.
都是我的错  我要弥补这一切
That's my failing. I've got to put it right.
-我说我整晚都和李在一起  -那是真的吗
- I said I was with Lee all night. - Was that true?
不  我当时在我朋友家里
No, I was at a friend's house.
-那天晚上发生了什么  -他给我下了药
- What happened that night? - He drugged me.
我早上5点醒来时他在打扫整个屋子
I woke up at 5.00 am and he was cleaning the whole house.
你和瑞奇的事我很遗憾
Sorry to hear about you and Ricky.
已经很长时间了
It was a long time coming.
甚至在他女儿被杀时
Even the moment his daughter was being killed
他还正在搞一个伴娘
he was shagging one of the bridesmaids.
婚礼上你们不是在一块吗
You were at the wedding together?
你之前一直说那晚你们在一起
You always said you were together that night.
你从没提过
You never mentioned that.
瑞奇  你离凯特远点
Ricky. You leave Cate alone.
为什么一个父亲不希望
Why would a father not want an investigation to restart
重新调查他女儿的死因
into the death of his own daughter?
也许李·阿什沃斯不是凶手
What if Lee Ashworth didn't do it?
进来吧  亲爱的  她不咬人
Come in, sweetheart. She won't bite.
-你不会哭出来吧  妈妈  -不会
- You're not gonna cry, are you, Mum? - No.
别那么跟你妈说话
Don't talk to your mum like that.
没事  谢谢  露西
It's fine, thanks, Luce.
谢谢你同意见我
Thanks for agreeing to see me.
露西姨妈说我非见不可
Aunt Lucy said I had to.
学校怎么样
How's school?
跟我说说庭审的事
Tell me about the trial.
真的吗
Really?
你以为这事不会被提起吗
Did you think we're not going to mention it?
好吧
Right, OK, er...
看到你父亲站在那里很艰难
Well, it's hard seeing your dad there.
如果你那么肯定是他干的
If you're so sure he did it,
他为什么申辩无罪
why is he pleading 'not guilty'?
我也希望我知道  我觉得他是怕了
I wish I knew but I think because he's scared
无法面对发生的事
and I think he can't bear to face up to  what's happened.
人有时会这样
People do that.
你错了
Well, you've got it wrong.
汤姆  我知道你希望是那样
Tom, I know you want that to be true
也知道你怪我
and I know you blame me.
但你爸杀了丹尼
But your dad killed Danny
如果我早发现发生了什么事
and if I could have spotted what was going on
如果我能回到过去  撤销一切
or if I could go back and make it un-happen,
我会的  但我做不到
I would, but I can't.
谁站在他那边  谁替爸爸说话
Who is on his side? Who's speaking up for Dad?
你不用担心他  他的出庭律师很厉害
You don't have to worry about him. He's got a good barrister.
我想提出的是
But what I wanted to suggest
希望你能回来跟我一起住
was that you came back to live with me
我不再住公寓了  我们回家住
and I give up the flat and we go back to the house.
不要
No.
-你能听我说说吗  -不要
- Would you just listen for a moment? - No!
我不会回去的
I am not going back.
那再过段时间吧
Well, soon, yeah?
不要
No.
好吧  至少跟我抱抱吧
OK. Can I at least have a hug?
我爱你  超过巧克力
I love you, even more than chocolate.
你不用跟我一起来审问这女人
You don't have to come with me to question this woman.
不  我想来  我的生活都毁了
No, I want to. My life has all gone to shit.
解决你的问题至少能让我分分心
At least fixing your mess gives me a distraction.
你要搬回去吗
Are you going to move back in here?
等汤姆愿回来的  我们去不去了
Only when I've got Tom back. Are we going or not?
你说你是哪里来的
Where did you say you were from?
南麦喜亚警方  我们在查一桩老案
South Mercia police. We're looking at an old case.
2012年4月14日  你是否作为伴娘
On 14 April 2012, were you the bridesmaid
参加了马丁和艾斯特-凯莉
for Martin and Esther Kelly's wedding
在朗索恩酒店的婚礼
at Longthorne Hotel?
我记不清日子了  但我的确去了婚礼
I don't know if that was the date but I was at the wedding.
你那晚是否跟一个
Did you have sex with a man
叫瑞奇·吉莱斯皮的男人上床了
called Ricky Gillespie that night?
你们真不是闹着玩的
Wow, you don't mess about!
女儿被杀的那个瑞奇吗
You mean Ricky whose girl was killed?
对
Yeah.
没有  他的确想泡我
No, I didn't. I mean, he tried it on.
一整晚都对我纠缠不休
He was after me all night.
我去换鞋的时候  甚至跟我回了房
He even followed me to my room when I went to change my shoes,
我当时的高跟疼死了
cos my heels were killing me,
他拿了个银酒壶
and he had this little silver hip flask.
一直想劝我跟他喝一杯
He kept trying to make me have a drink with him
但我让他出去了  太过分了
but I threw him out. A bit much.
他是跟妻子一起去的呢
He was there with his wife.
我最后看到他  他正往停车场去
The last I saw, he was heading back through the car park.
-他在你房里待了多久  -5到10分钟
- How long was he in your room for? - Five or ten minutes.
那晚再没见到他
I didn't see him for the rest of the evening.
凯特·吉莱斯皮错了
So Cate Gillespie was wrong.
瑞奇没跟别的女人在一起
Ricky wasn't with another woman.
他消失了两小时  他去哪了
Nobody saw him for two hours. Where was he?
谁会带酒壶去婚礼啊
And who takes a hip flask to a wedding?
你觉得他是想给她下药吗
Do you think he was going to drug her?
我没听过他做过这种事的报告
I haven't heard any reports of him trying that sort of thing.
克莱尔说李以前也那么对她
Claire said that's what Lee used to do to her.
你说他们四个会不会都那么做过
Do think it's something all four of them used to do?
我不知道
I don't know.
等今天法庭的事完了  我们去找她
When we're done in court today we'll talk to her.
你上次检查视力是什么时候了
When was the last time you had your eyesight tested?
夜视呢
What about your night vision?
做过测试吗
Ever had that tested?
没有
Never had a test.
但我常吃胡萝卜[治夜盲]
But I eat a lot of carrots.
所以说你并不清楚自己
So, you have no idea how far you can see
在白天和晚上的视域
either in the daytime or at night?
我能看见月亮  那够远吗
I can see the moon and that's a fair distance.
很好  能说说你儿子卡特先生吗
Very good. Can we turn to your son, Mr Carter?
你28年没见过他了  是吗
You hadn't seen him for 28 years, had you?
我知道他什么样  如果你是这个意思
I know what he looks like, if that's what you're getting at.
卡特先生给警方留下的宣誓证词中
In Mr Carter's sworn statement to the police he says,
他说"我根本不认识她"
"I don't even know who she is."
"我不想跟她有瓜葛"
"I don't want anything to do with her."
警方错了  警方常犯错
Police got it wrong. Police get it wrong all the time.
-就是这样  -不是的
- It's a fact. - It's not, actually.
你不是给她做过准备吗
I thought you'd prepped her.
她简直是个麻烦精
She's a bloody liability!
她跟我在一起时不这样
She wasn't like this with me.
请回答你被问到的问题  怀特女士
Stick to answering the questions you've been asked, Miss Wright.
好
Ok!
你最初在海滩上看到丹尼尸体的时候
When you first saw Danny's body on the beach,
你为什么没叫救护车
why didn't you call for an ambulance?
那时已经来不及了
A bit late by then.
你似乎很肯定啊  你核实过吗
You seem very certain. Did you check?
你有这个医疗资质吗
Are you medically qualified?
发生了什么显而易见
It was obvious what had happened.
但你为什么不报警呢
Why didn't you call the police?
我当时不想牵连奈杰
I didn't want to dump Nigel in it.
你如何解释警方鉴证发现
How do you explain police forensics finding
丹尼尸体附近有四根带有你DNA的烟头
four cigarette butts with your DNA on them next to Danny's body?
我经常在海滩上抽烟
I've smoked a lot of cigarettes on that beach.
-你为什么拿走滑板  -我担心被人偷走
- Why did you take the skateboard? - I thought it might get nicked.
的确被偷了啊  你偷了
It did get nicked, didn't it? By you!
我觉得他家人会想要回去
I thought the family would want it back.
你认识玛吉·雷德克里夫吗
Do you know who Maggie Radcliffe is?
不
No.
她是《广教镇回音报》编辑
The editor of the Broadchurch Echo.
你于2013年7月24日闯进了她的办公室
Whose office you broke into around 11.37pm on 24 July, 2013
你用我复述的这句"我能找到人强奸你"
and whom you threatened by saying, and I quote,
威胁了谁
"I know men who would rape you."
-什么  -我不知道这事
- What? - I don't have that.
这不是真的
Not true.
什么不是真的  你是虚张声势还是真能找到
What's not true? You don't know men like that or you do?
我从没说过这话
I never said it!
她为什么要说谎
Why would she lie?
-她是名记者  -是的
- She's a journalist. - Right!
记者和警察都说了谎
Journalists and police lie
而你是这里唯一诚实的女人
and you're the only honest woman here.
随你怎么说
If you like.
从你站上证人席起  在法庭上说的每一句话
Isn't it true that every word you have told this court
是不是都是假的
since you stood up in the witness box is a lie?
-不是  -你没看到奈杰·卡特
- No. - You didn't see Nigel Carter.
-你看到的是乔·米勒  -不是
- You saw Joe Miller. - No!
但你想把罪名推到弃你而去的儿子身上
But you want to pin the blame on the son who's rejected you.
-不是  -你在庭上一次又一次地撒谎
- No! - You've lied to this court time and again,
就像你向警方撒谎一样
just as you've lied to the police!
-不是  -陪审团为什么要相信你所说的话
- No! - Why should the jury believe a single word you say?
你别以为这就算赢了
You ain't all that.
要是我知道这些  我不会去找她当证人的
I wouldn't have gone anywhere near her if I'd seen that!
我知道  抱歉
I know. I'm sorry!
你知道吗  要是你少花点时间
Do you know what, maybe if you spent a little less time
对我指手画脚
trying to tell me how to do my job
多花点时间在你自己的工作上
and a bit more time on your own work
我们就有机会帮他正名了
we'd stand a chance of getting him off.
别灰心
Chin up.
在庭上撒谎  开心吗
Did you enjoy yourself, lying in there?
站在被告席上的可不是我的丈夫
It's not my husband in the dock.
-我想你肯定全都知道  -不
- I suppose you knew all along. - No!
你当然知情
Of course you did.
我们都清楚
We all know.
只是装作不知道罢了
We all turn a blind eye.
与我无关  事情不是这样的
Not me - that's not what happened.
是啊
Of course not.
你就继续这么骗自己吧
You just keep telling yourself that.
-你还好吗  -他们总觉得我早就知道这事
- Are you all right? - They'll always think I knew.
无论判决如何  他们始终觉得我也有份
No matter what the verdict, they'll always think I was in on it.
给人们点时间
Just give them time.
真是个好主意
Oh, brilliant.
谢谢你的狗屁客套话  解决了一切麻烦
Thanks for that shitty platitude. That's fixed everything.
-克莱尔知道我们要去吗  -不知道
- Does Claire know we're coming? - No.
关于那晚的事
I want you to tell me
我要你把告诉米勒的话完整地说给我听
what you told Miller about that night.
我以为这事只有你我知道
That was supposed to be between us.
我和他之间没有秘密
There are no secrets between him and me.
是吗
Is that right?
克莱尔  我不管你之前说了什么
Claire, I don't care what you've said before.
现在我想要知道真相
I want the truth now.
正如我之前跟你说的那样
That night I went to see a friend, Marie,
那晚我去见了一个朋友  名叫玛丽
like I told you before.
但是...
Except...
我没在她家过夜  我回家和李喝酒了
I didn't stay over. I came home and I had a drink with Lee.
我觉得他在我的酒里下了安眠药
I think he spiked my drink with Rohypnol.
我睡了很久  当我醒来的时候已经是早上了
I was out for a long time and when I woke, it was morning.
-他在打扫屋子  -怎么个打扫法
- He was cleaning. - What sort of cleaning?
打扫卫生间  洗床单
Bathroom. Washing linen.
吸尘  擦洗地板
Hoovering. Washing floors.
他说他想来个春季大扫除
He said he fancied a spring clean.
他先给你下了药  然后打扫屋子
So, he's drugged you, now he's cleaning the house
第二天早上隔壁家两个女孩
and the next morning two girls
被报失踪
get reported missing from next door
而你不觉得该把这事告诉别人吗
but you don't think to tell anyone?
我不想那样怀疑他
I didn't want to think it was possible.
现在呢
What about now?
-你觉得会是他杀了那两个女孩吗  -不
- Do you think he could have killed those girls? - No.
关于那晚的事  这是你所说的第三个版本了
This is now the third version of that night you've come up with.
之前你为什么不告诉我这些
Why couldn't you tell me this before?
我不想让你知道他对我做了什么
I didn't want you knowing what he used to do to me.
你要做什么
What are you doing?
这是谁的电话号码
Whose number's that?
我不知道  这是通打进来的电话
I don't know. It was an incoming call.
-我以为是打错了  -这是拨出去的号码
- I think it was a wrong number. - It was an outgoing call.
对  我想回拨过去确认下  通了后...
Yeah, because I called it back to check and it just rang and-
这个区域号是你和李居住的地方的
This area code, that's where you lived with Lee.
-我觉得你在讯问我  -没错
- Now I feel I'm being questioned! - Too bloody right!
你是我的关键证人
You were my key witness
现在你却说一直在撒谎
and now you say you're lying all along.
-我没撒谎  -那是什么
- I'm not lying! - What, then?
-我是想保护他  -保护他还是保护你自己
- Trying to protect him. - Him or yourself?
这不公平
That's not fair!
最后再问一遍
So this is now definitively,
刚才所说是那晚发生的一切吗
this is what happened that night?
是的
Yes.
真的吗
Really?
克莱尔
Claire?
还有...
There is erm...
你走那天他来了这里  我们在楼上做了
He was here when you went away and we had sex upstairs.
什么  克莱尔
What, Claire?!
你抛下我一人  亚力克
You left me alone, Alec.
我跟你说过  对我而言他就像毒品
And you, I've told you, he's like a drug to me.
我控制不住我自己  根本控制不住
I can't stop myself! I can't!
-走吧  米勒  -你们这就走了
- Come on, Miller. - Are you going?
我不想一个人待在这
I don't want to be on my own, please.
要看孩子  抱歉
Child care. Sorry.
那现在怎么办
What happens now, then?
米勒
Miller!
之前我们说起的那件事
The thing we were speaking about -
和改过自新的性犯罪者会面
meeting reformed sex offenders.
-我替你安排好了  -好的  真快啊
- I've managed to arrange it for you. - Oh, right. That was quick.
你还想跟他们会面吗
You still want to do it?
想的吧  我也不知道  我有点害怕
I think so. I don't know. I'm a bit scared of it.
我和玛吉也会在场的
Maggie and I will be there too.
我知道关于庭审你有很多事要忙
I know you've got a lot on with the trial,
要是你想推迟...
so if you want to delay...
-不  没关系  -马克呢
- No, it's good. - What about Mark?
我会跟他说的
I'll talk to him.
好  那我挂了
OK, I'd better go,
等细节定下来我再联系你
but I'll let you know the details once it's all set.
-好的  再见  -再见
- OK. Bye-bye. - Bye.
你是不是个漂亮的小女孩
Aren't you a beautiful little girlie?
你是  对吗  我知道你是
You are, aren't you? You are, I know.
就是这么爱动  对不对啊
Yeah. Little wriggler, aren't you?
-带她看风景  -对
- Showing her the sights? - Yeah.
告诉她法庭上发生了什么
Telling her what's happening in court.
她才不想听  对不对
She doesn't want to hear that! Do you, darling?
她当然想听  她很感兴趣
Of course she does - she's interested.
谁在支持我们  谁在说谎
Who's sticking up for us, who's telling lies.
你怎么样
How are you feeling?
很好  我们说过以丹尼的名义做点事情
Yeah. You know we talked about doing something in Danny's name?
-是的  -你怎么这个语气
- Right... - What have you got that voice on for?
我语气很正常
I haven't got any voice on.
就是有  好像你不感兴趣
Yeah, your are, like you're not interested.
-我们非得要谈这个  -为什么你不参加
- Do we have to talk about this? - Why won't you engage with this?
因为我不明白为什么
Because I don't understand why...
我不明白你为什么要这么做  真的
I don't understand why you need to do it, I don't, I really don't.
就像要揭开伤疤  让它流血
You're picking at a scab, trying to make it bleed or something.
-什么  -看看我们的女儿
- What? - Look at what we've got here.
你也知道  转眼她就长大了
You know what it's like, she'll be grown up before we know it
我不想再错过
and I don't want to miss that again.
我想每时每刻都陪着她
I want to be here for her, every moment.
我也在陪着她  但我还想着丹尼
I'm here for her, but I can still think about Danny.
这是两码事  我需要这么做  马克
It's not one or the other. I need to do this. Mark.
好吧  我不想
Fine. I don't.
我们寄信给你
We sent you a letter
请你做乔·米勒的品行证人
asking you to be a character witness for Joe Miller.
-乔真的指望着你  -我拒绝过了
- Joe is really relying on you. - I've said no.
乔·米勒有罪
Joe Miller is guilty.
他确实向你认罪了吗
Has he ever categorically confessed his guilt to you?
没有
No.
为什么不让陪审团决定
Why not let the jury decide?
还有  如果你确定他有罪
Besides, if you're so sure about his guilt,
为什么还去探视他
why have you been visiting him?
他告诉你了
He told you?
律师和委托人之间没有秘密
There are no secrets between a barrister and her client.
就像告解秘密
Like the Seal of the Confessional.
告解秘密  向神父忏悔时说话  神父都会保密
我去探视他
I went to see him
是因为我坚信宽恕和赎罪
because I believe in forgiveness and redemption.
我希望他能悔过  可自从你出现
I hoped to find a repentant man, but since you showed up
这好像不可能了
that seems to have gone out the window.
丹尼葬礼上你做了礼拜  对吗
You gave the service at Danny's funeral, didn't you?
是的
I did.
拉蒂默夫妇知道你曾探视过乔吗
Do the Latimers know you've been visiting Joe?
-这是干什么  轮流审问吗  -听着
- What is this? Bad cop, bad cop? - Look...
我懂了  你不想作证
I get it. You don't want to give evidence,
因为你怕拉蒂默夫妇觉得被背叛了
because you're worried the Latimers will feel betrayed.
不  绝不是这样
No, that is not it!
世人都犯了罪  亏缺了神的荣耀
"All have sinned and fall short of the glory of God."
罗马书3:23
Romans 3.23.
不只有你按时做礼拜  牧师
You are not the only churchgoer here, Reverend.
你教区的一位信徒身陷囹圄
Now, a member of your parish is in crisis.
你真的要在危难关头抛弃他吗
Are you really going to desert him in his hour of need?
再想想  好吗
Have another think about it, would you?
我喜欢你的教堂
I like your church.
看吧  出来走走有好处
See? It's good to get out.
你待在死人旁边的时间太多了
You spend way too much time around dead people.
是要我继续自言自语
Shall I just keep talking
还是你能和我说说话
or are you going to join in at some point?
贝卡  有件事我要告诉你
Becca, there's something I want to tell you.
我去监狱探视过乔·米勒
I've been visiting Joe Miller in prison.
和他一起祈祷过
Praying with him.
你开玩笑呢吧
You're kidding.
我以为我能拯救他
I thought I could save him.
我以为他会悔过
I thought he was repentant.
悔过  开庭时你不在场吗
Repentant? Have you not been at the trial?!
贝卡  我觉得我犯了一个错误
Becca, I think I've made a mistake.
我必须找人倾诉
I just needed to tell someone.
说话啊
Say something.
你让我感觉  我也参与了
I feel like you've made me a part of it.
我把这些文件的录音发给你了
I sent you those audio files of those documents read onto tape.
很好  我要你把这些录成语音
Oh good. Now, I need you to read and record these as well.
-什么  -还有这些
- What? - And...these.
以及这些
And these.
拜托了
Please?
-我做不到  -你必须做
- I can't! - Well, you have to.
乔瑟琳  我还有很多事要做
Jocelyn I have far too much else to do.
那就干活麻利点
Well, then, work faster!
不行  你自己读不行吗
No! Read your own documents.
我可不要熬夜到凌晨三点念文件
I'm not sitting up to 3.00am reading aloud
好让你坐着闭眼听
so you can sit back with your eyes closed.
我不能这么工作  你真是个噩梦
I can't work like this! You're a bloody nightmare.
我要回家陪家人了
I'm going home to see my family.
明天法庭见
I'll see you tomorrow at court.
别这么看我
Don't give me that look!
-你听到多少  -足够了
- How much did you hear? - Enough.
你还没告诉他  对吗
You haven't told him, have you?
碰碰车  哈迪
Oh, bumper cars, Hardy!
这真是太棒了
I think this is brilliant!
当时你知道家后面要建这个吗
Did you not know this was going to be behind your house?
签约时房屋出租公司忘了提
The rental company forgot to mention it when I took it on.
弗雷德  我们去坐一趟  好不
Oh, Fred, we could go on the teacups, couldn't we?
可以带上亚力克叔叔
We could take uncle Alec.
瑞奇  你怎么会在这里
Ricky, what are you doing here?
这真是你家
Is this really your gaff?
抱歉  我是瑞奇·吉莱斯皮
Sorry. Ricky Gillespie.
我是艾莉·米勒  同事
Ellie Miller. We work together.
你来这里干什么
What are you doing here?
我来道歉
I came to apologise.
凯特告诉我你来过  我反应过度了
When Cate told me you'd been around, I overreacted.
跑这么远就说这个
A long way to come to say that.
我知道阿什沃斯在这  你看到他了吗
I know Ashworth is down here. You seen him?
告诉我他在哪
Tell me where he is.
没必要  瑞奇  这对谁都没好处
There's no need, Ricky, that won't help anyone.
听说他回国了我简直寝食难安
It's eating me up knowing he's back in the country.
你真想帮忙  和米勒谈谈
You really want to help? Talk to Miller here.
她在重新梳理案子
She's going through the case
看看我们忽略了什么
looking to see if we've missed anything.
你想知道什么
What do you want to know?
躲不了我哦  伙计
Can't hide from me, mate!
跟我说说你女儿皮帕
Tell me about your daughter Pippa.
她是我的宝贝女儿
She was my baby girl, you know.
热爱运动
She was sporty.
跑步健将
Good runner.
在校队打篮网球
Played netball for the school team.
乒乓球大师
Demon at table tennis.
好胜
Competitive.
不喜欢输
Didn't like losing.
我一向宠她
I always spoilt her.
独生女
My only child.
她长大后想干什么
What did she want to be when she grew up?
一直在变
It kept changing.
最后几个月是...
The last few months it was er...
美发师
hairdresser.
两个女孩失踪的那晚
The night both girls disappeared,
你和凯特在参加婚礼
you were at a wedding with Cate.
你们一整晚都在一起吗
You were together all night?
我不得不照顾她  她喝醉了
I had to look after her. She was pissed.
就像是对将要发生的事的预兆
Sign of things to come, 'ey?
跟我说说丽莎
And tell me about Lisa.
她是我侄女
She was my niece.
跟她爸爸的关系挺僵的  还跟着妈妈姓
Tricky relationship with her dad. Still uses her mum's surname.
-她常来帮你看孩子吗  -隔周来一次
- She babysat for you quite regularly? - Every other week.
有时她会过夜  其他时候我会送她回家
Sometimes she'd stay over, other times I'd take her home.
-她有男友吗  -没有固定的
- Did she have a boyfriend? - No-one regular.
你喜欢她吗  瑞奇
Did you fancy her, Ricky?
她是我侄女
She was my niece.
例行公事罢了
I had to ask.
不  才不是
No, you didn't.
-你还好吗  -没事
- You all right? - Fine.
你当初对瑞奇的调查有多深入
How much did you look into Ricky at the time?
他有可靠的不在场证明
He had a solid alibi.
他和凯特说他们一同在参加婚礼
He and Cate said they were at the wedding together.
她改口了  花商证实了
She's changed her story and the florist confirmed it.
-看上去他在撒谎  -看上去是的
- Looks like he's lying. - Looks that way.
那么我们的嫌犯是哪几个
So, who are our suspects?
阿什沃斯  里奇  克莱尔还有那个跟踪者
Got Ashworth, Ricky, Claire, and that stalker on the estate.
-也可能是凯特  -对  不要相信任何人
- Possibly Cate. - That's right, don't trust anyone.
你该回去了  带上弗雷德  好好睡一觉
You should go. Take Fred. Sleep.
现在我不怎么睡觉  我也不喜欢我的公寓
I don't sleep much at the moment, and I don't like my flat
我还想好好看看你那些文件
and I want to take a proper look at all your files.
别陷得这么深
Don't get pulled into this.
这个案子对大家造成的伤害已经够多了
This case has done enough damage to people.
不会伤害我  我会破了这个案
Not me. I'm going to solve it.
我要借你的墙一用
I'm going to need your wall.
你在外面没事吧
You all right out there?
要哄小熊睡觉吗
You going to put your bear to sleep?
她以前也有只熊
She used to have a bear too.
我去走走
I'm going for a walk.
把钥匙留在那下面
Leave the key under the thing.
好
Ok.
老天  我得给大门加把锁了
Oh, for heaven's sake! I need a lock put on that gate.
你忙吗
You busy?
我当然忙了  正办案子呢
Of course I'm busy. I'm in the middle of a trial!
有何贵干
What do you want?
能帮我立遗嘱吗
Could you do my will?
也就你会把我当做商业律师
Anyone would think I was a high-street solicitor.
又不复杂
It's not exactly complicated.
全部给你的女儿
So, everything to your daughter.
留到她十八岁时  幸运的姑娘
Held till she is 18. Hm, lucky girl.
-你有孩子吗  -终生未嫁
- You got kids? - I never married.
是有意为之吗
That through choice?
这是要干什么  警方问讯吗
What is this, a police interview?
不是  抱歉  只是聊聊
No. Sorry. Just conversation.
好吧
Well...
事情曾经很复杂  我让其变得尤为复杂
Things were complicated and I made... I made them more so.
当时  我本应该强大一点的
I was at a point when I, when I should have been strong
但我没有
and I wasn't,
我错了本应共度一生的那个人
and I missed the person I was supposed to be with.
你有告诉过他吗
Did you ever tell him?
没有
No.
也许你应该告诉他
Maybe you should.
事后意识到错误很容易
It's always easy to recognise mistakes in hindsight.
要解决起来可就难多了
Much harder to fix them now.
你为何要现在立遗嘱
Anyway, why do you... why do you need this now?
做我该做的
Just putting things right.
你如何看待审判
What's your sense of the trial?
苏珊·怀特对辩方不利
Susan Wright was a mistake for the defence.
让他们看起来很不专业
It makes them look like amateurs.
不出席证人席作证
Not going into the witness
将有损米勒的可信度
box is going to damage Miller's credibility.
一定要给他定罪
He has got to be convicted.
用不着你告诉我
I don't need you to tell me that!
我会竭尽所能的
I'll do the best I can with what I have.
她怎么还不睡  都喂了两顿了
Why won't she sleep? She's had two feeds.
给我吧  来
Give her to me, come on.
交给我吧  你回去睡
I've got her. You go back to bed.
乖
That's it.
乖  乖
That's it, that's it.
嘘  我知道
Shh. I know.
我们该拿你怎么办呢  小麻烦
What are we going to do with you? Troubling.
你这大喊大闹的把大家都吵醒了
You're making all that racket and waking everyone up.
我们该拿你怎么办呢
What are we going to do with you?
看见这个了吗
Did you see this scribbled
一张旧的车辆检查表背面的潦草字迹
on the back of an old vehicle check form?
索普乡镇农业服务
Thorp Agriservices.
那是什么  你有看见过吗
What's that? Have you come across that?
接着是加里·索普  连字符  李·阿什沃斯  问号
And next to it, Gary Thorp, Dash, Lee Ashworth, question mark.
-你一整晚都在这吗  -我想是的
- Have you been here all night? - Yeah, I suppose I have.
弗雷德在隔壁睡着呢  嘘
Fred is sleeping next door. Shh!
我要喝杯茶
I need a cup of tea.
你的茶包和牛奶都没了
Ah, you're out of teabags and milk
最后一点面包也被我吃了
and I've used the last of the bread.
我没找到任何
I couldn't find any note of Thorp Agriservices
复查索普乡镇农业服务的记录
ever being cross-checked.
我好像没听说过这个名字
I don't think I've ever heard of it.
我还看了一遍李·阿什沃斯给你的资料
Plus, I went through that stuff Lee Ashworth gave you.
要么没用  要么无关
It's all useless or irrelevant.
他只是想转移我们的视线
He's just trying to put us off the scent.
你对丽莎·纽伯瑞调查了多少
How far did you ever look into Lisa Newbery?
什么意思
How do you mean?
丽莎最后使用银行账户的时间
The last use of Lisa's bank account
是她失踪那天下午3点54分
was at 3:54 pm on the day she disappeared
在她去做保姆之前
before she went to babysit.
最后一条通话记录是在
The last call was made at 5:17 pm
晚上5点17分从手机打给她妈妈
on her mobile to her mum.
之后便再没取钱或是通话了
Then no more cash withdrawals or calls made after that,
但她的手机却一直开机18小时
but her phone was on for another 18 hours.
最后的定位地点在朴茨茅斯
The last signal triangulated in Portsmouth.
她的手机怎么跑到朴茨茅斯去了
How the hell did her phone get to Portsmouth?
当时有嫌疑人住在朴茨茅斯附近吗
Were any of our suspects near Portsmouth then?
没有  我们查过了  这些我们都知道
No, we checked. We know all this.
我的想法是这样的
OK, here's the thing.
丽莎失手杀死了皮帕
Lisa killed Pippa by accident.
处理了尸体逃跑了
Got rid of the body and went on the run.
凶手是她  而且她还活着
She did that and she's still alive.
你得承认  有这种可能
You've got to admit, it's a possibility.
-准备好了吗  -好了
- You ready? - Yeah
走吧
Come on.
你是检方的反驳证人
You're a prosecution rebuttal witness.
你的作用是反驳辩方的一部分观点
You are there specifically to rebut part of the defence case.
你好  卡特先生  当晚有人跟你在一起吗
Hello, Mr Carter. Was anyone with you that night?
没有
No.
-有人看到你了吗  -没有
- Did anyone see you? - No.
所以没人能证实你的说法
So, nobody can corroborate your story?
只有我煮熟的野鸡能证明
Only the pheasants I poached.
你觉得这好玩吗  卡特先生
Is this funny to you, Mr Carter?
不好玩
Not at all.
你的亲生母亲指认你出现在丹尼的尸体旁
Your own mother identified you with Danny's body, didn't she?
如果是我杀了丹尼
If I killed Danny,
那他身上应该有我的DNA吧
then where is my DNA on him, 'ey?
小屋里也没有我的指纹吧
Where are my prints at the hut?
谁说是你杀了丹尼
Who said you killed him?
我可没有暗示说是你杀了丹尼
I'm not suggesting you killed Danny.
我暗示的是你将他的尸体放到了海滩上
I am suggesting that you put his body on the beach
并且被苏珊·怀特看到了
where Susan Wright saw you.
-是这样吗  -不是
- Isn't that correct? - No!
谢谢你
Thank you.
伙计
Mate...
出什么事了
What happened?
告诉我到底怎么回事
Tell me what it was about.
有目击证人吗
Were there witnesses?
他们知道是谁下的手吗  有人为此受罚吗
Do they know who did this? Is someone being punished for this?
你现在受到应有的保护了吗
Are you getting proper protection now?
乔纳  说话啊
Jonah, say something!
从我小时候你就说"我是你妈妈
Ever since I was a boy you said, "I'm your mum.
告诉我  我来帮你搞定"
Tell me, and I'll make it all right."
那你怎么不能救我出去
Why can't you get me out of here?
不  这不是你的错  你已经尽力了
No, it's not your fault. You did your best.
好了  别担心了  明天见
All right, stop worrying now. I'll see you tomorrow.
再见
Yeah, bye.
是奈杰打来的  他...
That was Nige. He's er...
今天的事让他很难过
He's all torn up about today.
我告诉他我们不担心  他也不用担心
I told him we weren't worried, so he shouldn't be.
贝丝
Beth?
可我担心
I do worry, though.
我担心陪审团会相信她
I worry the jury will believe her.
我担心已有的事实不够定他的罪
I worry the truth won't be enough.
索普乡镇农业服务
你查过他之前跟谁在一起了吗
怎么了
What?
你告诉瑞奇·吉莱斯皮我在哪工作了吗
Did you tell Ricky Gillespie where I was working?
没有  怎么了
No, why?
因为他来找我了
Because he's come for me.
给你
Here you go.
见鬼
Oh, shit!
瑞奇  住手  瑞奇
Ricky, get off him! Ricky!
快住手  别打了
Get off him. Come on!
你觉得这有用吗
Do you think that will help?
我就是来打他的
I got what I came for.
一无是处的混蛋
You're nothing!
你要报案吗
Are you going to report it?
不了  报案有用吗
No, what's the point?
你就睡在这吗
Is this where you're sleeping?
农场主说可以
The farmer said I could.
我喜欢
I like it.
我听说你见了克莱尔
I hear you saw Claire.
是吗
Did you?
你们俩用过氟硝安定[催眠药]吗
You two ever use Rohypnol?
-用过一次  -从哪弄到的
- Once. - Where did you get it from?
瑞奇·吉莱斯皮
Ricky Gillespie.
他去过阿姆斯特丹
He used to go to Amsterdam,
带回来了各种各样的东西
bring back all sorts of stuff.
-瑞奇给了你氟硝安定[催眠药]  -没错
- Ricky gave you Rohypnol? - He did.
你听说过一家叫索普乡镇农业服务的公司吗
Have you ever heard of a business called Thorp Agriservices?
没有
No.
你确定吗
You sure about that?
除非凯特帮它做过账
Unless it's one of the businesses Cate did the books for.
你跟凯特睡过吗
Did you ever sleep with Cate?
-妈妈再见  -再见  宝贝  一天愉快
- Bye, Mum! - Bye, sweetheart. Have a great day.
没有
No.
辩方想让陪审团相信是我杀了丹
The defence want the jury to believe that I killed Dan.
然后找奈杰销毁尸体
Got Nige to dispose of the body.
他们就是这么打算的
That's clearly where they're going.
我曾读过一个经历这种的事的家庭
I was reading about another family.
他们说审判
They were saying the trial
跟谋杀一样恐怖  我还想着
was as bad as the murder and I thought,
"他们说的不对"
"That can't be right."
可我现在每天走进法庭
Then going in every day,
眼睁睁地看着我们的生活被打乱...
seeing our lives get turned inside out...
而我们只是很爱我们的儿子
when all we did was love our son.
我终于体会到了
I get it.
你想让我作为证人出庭  对吧
You want me to go in the witness box, don't you?
说实话吗  我很纠结
Honestly? I'm torn.
丹尼被杀的那晚
There's an hour missing in your account
你有一个小时的时间不知去向
the night Danny was killed.
你不用保护我  乔瑟琳
You don't need to protect me, Jocelyn
你自己也说过得有人为丹站出来
You said yourself somebody needs to speak up for Dan. Well...
我是他爸爸  这是我应该做的
I'm his dad. It should be down to me, you know.
-马克不来  -是的
- No Mark? - No.
他们来了吗
They're here.
是的  他们跟小组的领导在里面
Yep, they're inside with the group leader.
为什么我又要见一次
Why am I doing this again?
可能这太快了
Maybe this is too soon.
不不不  我可以  我能面对他们
No, no, no, I can do it. I can face them.
什么事
What?
你好啊  你好像走错房间了
Hello. I think you're in the wrong room.
我是汤姆·米勒
I'm Tom Miller.
乔·米勒是我爸爸
Joe Miller is my dad.
可不是  我没认出来
Of course you are. I didn't recognise you.
-你来这干什么  -你们为什么不让我出庭
- What are you doing here? - Why don't you call me in court?
我想去作证
I want to give evidence.
早上好
Good morning.
-你刚才说什么  -早上好
- What did you say?! - Good morning.
正常人不都这么说吗
Isn't that what people normally say?
你竟然跟我说正常人...
You talk about being normal...
这是我儿子  你看看监狱的人对他做了什么
That's my son! That's what they've done to him in prison!
这事你怪不得我
Don't you dare make this my responsibility.
对啊  因为你不食人间烟火  对吧
Of course not! Life doesn't touch you, does it?
好了  莎伦
All right, Sharon.
我劳心劳力地为你工作了七年
Seven years I took shit from you!
七年啊
Seven years,
我唯一一次求你办件事
and the one time I ask you for anything,
你却不理不问
you don't raise a finger.
我为什么总要帮你收拾乱摊子
Why should I be always mopping up your mess?
-什么  -你为我工作的那段时间
- What?! - All the time you worked for me.
总在说你是个可怜的单身母亲
All those 'poor me single mother' speeches.
别怪在我身上  都是你一手造成的
Don't put this on me! It's down to you and no-one else.
你知道做母亲是什么感觉吗
What would you know about being a mother?
你连个人都不算
You're barely bloody human!
你儿子害死了一个人
A man died because of your boy.
是的  可他当时是在帮助别人
Yes, he was trying to help someone in trouble.
这句辩词说了多少遍了
Haven't we heard that defence before
你当时为什么不接他的案子
Why didn't you take his case?
因为我不够喜欢你
Because I didn't like you enough...
而且我就知道如果你输了会怪我
and I always knew you would blame me if you lost,
因为你一直都这样
because that's what you always did.
每次你输了案子
Every time you didn't win,
每次忘了重要论点
every time you missed out on a big brief,
你总是怪罪别人
you always blame someone else.
我原来对你期望很高
I had such high expectations of you.
你不应该再重新工作  乔瑟琳
You should have stayed retired, Jocelyn,
因为这次我会让你一败涂地
because I'm going to see that you leave that court a failure.
索普乡镇农业服务
Thorp Agriservices.
我上网查了下  是桑布鲁克地区的一家工厂
I Googled it. It's a business in the Sandbrook area
距离吉莱斯皮家五英里
five miles from the Gillespie house.
我得去乡镇农业服务看看
I need to visit this Thorp Agriservices place.
看一下你发现皮帕的地方以及河边的树林
I could see where you found Pippa and the woods by the river.
换个视角  就像你所期望的
Fresh eyes - that's what you wanted.
终于找到你了  你怎么不接电话
There you are! Don't you answer your phone?
我在满世界找你
I've been looking all over for you.
这是些什么破东西
What the hell is all that stuff?
不好意思  这可是我家
Excuse me. This is my house!
有什么事  露西
What do you want, Lucy?
我只是想告诉你我不知道他那么做了
I just want you to know I didn't know he'd done it.
不知道他做什么了
Didn't know he'd done what?
汤姆要为乔出庭作证
Tom is going to give evidence on behalf of Joe.
什么
What?
他背着我去见了乔的律师
He went to see Joe's legal team without my knowing.
没有我的允许他不能出庭  对吧
He can't do that without my permission, can he?
显然不是的
Apparently, he can.
我劝过他  可他下定决心了  艾
I tried to talk him out of it, but he's dead set on it, Elle.
-艾  -走吧  露西  快走吧
- Elle... - Just go away, Luce, go away!
丽莎的手机在朴茨茅斯
So, Lisa's phone in Portsmouth.
在朴茨茅斯
What do you do in Portsmouth
除了当海军或者看船还能干什么
apart from being in the navy or looking at ships?
-继续  告诉我吧  -可以坐船去法国
- Go on, dazzle me. - You get a ferry to France.
-朴茨茅斯到切尔博格  -然后呢
- Portsmouth to Cherbourg. - So?
-还有谁在法国  -李·阿什沃斯
- So, who else was in France? - Lee Ashworth.
没错  好了  就是这里
Exactly. OK, this is the place.
他们是干什么的
What is it they do?
服务农业的
Services to the agricultural industries.
我实在找不到更详细的介绍了
I couldn't find anything more specific than that.
不像是跟李·阿什沃斯有关的地方
It doesn't seem like a place Lee Ashworth would be connected to.
他有什么在瞒着我们呢
So, what is he not telling us?
好像关门很久了
It looks pretty closed.
肯定是不干了
It must have gone out of business.
去后面看看
Let's look round the back.
汤姆作证前你会跟他谈谈吗
Are you going to talk to Tom before he gets in the box?
我不想说这事
I don't want to talk about it.
什么味道
What's that smell?
是血
It's blood!
那是什么
What is that?!
看好了
Oh, look, here you go.
天哪  是个熔炉
Oh, God. It's a furnace.
农业服务  他们在这里焚烧死牲畜
Agricultural services - they burned dead animals here.
你还认为丽莎·纽伯瑞活着吗
You still think Lisa Newbery is alive?